<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<review>
  <metadata>
    <file>scripts/deploy.sh</file>
    <language>Sh</language>
    <loc>37</loc>
    <reviewer>AI-Claude</reviewer>
    <date>2025-07-08</date>
    <status>complete</status>
  </metadata>

  <scores>
    <metric name="security" score="3" open_issues="1"/>
    <metric name="performance" score="4" open_issues="1"/>
    <metric name="maintainability" score="2" open_issues="2"/>
    <metric name="consistency" score="4" open_issues="0"/>
    <metric name="best_practices" score="3" open_issues="1"/>
    <metric name="code_smell" score="3" open_issues="1"/>
  </scores>

  <issues>
    <issue category="security" severity="MEDIUM">
      <title>No Environment Variable Validation</title>
      <location>Lines 8-10</location>
      <description>Environment variables and configuration are not validated for security. The script assumes npm and deployment tools are available without verification.</description>
      <recommendation>Add validation for required environment variables and verify tool availability before execution</recommendation>
    </issue>
    <issue category="performance" severity="LOW">
      <title>Sequential Build and Test Execution</title>
      <location>Lines 20-24</location>
      <description>Build and test processes run sequentially which may be inefficient for larger projects</description>
      <recommendation>Consider parallelizing independent operations where possible</recommendation>
    </issue>
    <issue category="maintainability" severity="HIGH">
      <title>Missing Actual Deployment Logic</title>
      <location>Lines 29, 33</location>
      <description>Production and staging deployment sections contain only placeholder comments with no actual implementation</description>
      <recommendation>Implement actual deployment logic or reference external deployment scripts</recommendation>
    </issue>
    <issue category="maintainability" severity="MEDIUM">
      <title>Limited Error Handling</title>
      <location>Throughout file</location>
      <description>While 'set -e' is used, there's no specific error handling for different failure scenarios</description>
      <recommendation>Add specific error handling for build failures, test failures, and deployment failures</recommendation>
    </issue>
    <issue category="best_practices" severity="MEDIUM">
      <title>No Rollback Mechanism</title>
      <location>Lines 27-35</location>
      <description>Deployment script lacks rollback capability in case of deployment failure</description>
      <recommendation>Implement rollback mechanism and deployment verification steps</recommendation>
    </issue>
    <issue category="code_smell" severity="LOW">
      <title>Hardcoded Application Name</title>
      <location>Line 10</location>
      <description>Application name is hardcoded in the script instead of being configurable</description>
      <recommendation>Make application name configurable through environment variables or parameters</recommendation>
    </issue>
  </issues>

  <summary>A basic deployment script for vibe-check-demo that handles environment validation, building, testing, and deployment workflow. The script follows good bash practices with error handling (set -e) but lacks actual deployment implementation and advanced features like rollback mechanisms.</summary>

  <positive_observations>
    <observation>Uses 'set -e' for proper error handling and script termination on failures</observation>
    <observation>Clear environment validation with appropriate error messages</observation>
    <observation>Good separation of concerns with distinct phases (build, test, deploy)</observation>
    <observation>Informative echo statements for deployment process visibility</observation>
    <observation>Proper parameter handling with default values</observation>
  </positive_observations>

  <context>
    <tests>No dedicated tests for the deployment script itself</tests>
    <documentation>Minimal inline comments explaining the deployment flow</documentation>
    <configuration>Uses environment variables for deployment target configuration</configuration>
  </context>

  <checklist>
    <item completed="true">Lints clean</item>
    <item completed="false">Tests present</item>
    <item completed="false">Documentation updated</item>
    <item completed="true">Security review complete</item>
    <item completed="true">Performance acceptable</item>
  </checklist>
</review>